-Morning, Madhavi.
-Good morning, Madhavi.
Good morning.
What's the matter? It's Sunday!
Yeah.
What happened?
We have to head to Srinagar.
Pack your bags.
Sangy is flying Mirages now
and Chou sir is on leave,
so we all have to go.
-Okay.
-See you, Madhavi.
See you, Madhavi.
Last night in the Kargil sector, a major
ammunition depot of the Indian Army
was bombed to smithereens
by unknown intruders.
And today, the Kargil magistrate's house
has also been targeted.
Tololing Complex, located amongst
the treacherous peaks of Kargil sector,
and located closest
to the Srinagar-Leh Highway,
has witnessed constant firing.
-Shortage of ammunition and supplies has…
-Sir.
The ISI chief has called three times.
What should we do?
Indian DGMO?
Sir, I've already lied to the Indian DGMO.
But we'll have to tell
the ISI chief the truth.
No need, General.
Didn't the chief show Mian sahib
the captured posts from Skardu?
Yes, but he doesn't know
they're on the other side of the LoC.
Yes. But that's exactly our plan.
Sir, before Mian sahib
hears it from someone else--
Organize a briefing.
The time has come
for the prime minister to play his part.
Sardar, do you remember
when we were newly married?
I was in the habit of waking up late.
And you flew your MiG
over our house
every morning to wake me up.
If you don't want me to get back
into the habit of waking up late again,
come back to wake me up.
Can't you stay still?
It'll just take two minutes.
I have to finish packing.
Do we have to do this now?
Then when? Your birthday is coming up.
It's just a small mission.
I'll be back before my birthday.
Don't you worry.
I am not worrying. Turn.
Welcome to GHQ, Mian sahib.
I don't understand
the purpose of this urgent meeting.
Come, Mian sahib.
Let's sit down and discuss.
Shall we?
Tell me,
what do you want to brief me on?
Sir,
as per your wish, our freedom fighters
braving the harsh winter,
have occupied many new peaks
in the valley.
Some of those posts are across LoC.
Sir, these are the posts overlooking NH1
that Chief showed you in Skardu.
As Chief had briefed you--
General Musharraf, has the Army forgotten
how to answer direct questions?
This is the LoC, sir.
Every single captured post
across the LoC
are Indian posts.
Good morning, gentlemen.
You have all been summoned here
at extremely short notice.
Because the Kargil, Drass,
and Batalik sectors
are seeing heavy attacks on our army.
And it seems like
a highly coordinated attack.
-Oak.
-Sir.
The army's ammunition dump
has been blown up.
Their recce helicopters
have also been heavily damaged.
National Highway 1,
connecting Srinagar and Leh-Ladakh
has been completely cut off.
Army supplies are getting affected.
Now, for those unfamiliar
with this terrain.
This stretch of Drass, Kargil, and Batalik
is a 115 kilometer stretch.
Right now,
it is a black hole for the army.
Quite frankly,
it is for us too.
And so, air combat
and bombing squadrons will be on standby,
until Golden Arrows find the answer
to the most fundamental question…
Who are we fighting?
Then why not be clear about it?
That these aren't Mujahideen,
but the Pakistani Army.
As far as I can remember,
you never made this clear
to Mian sahib in Skardu.
For the world and India,
technically, they are Mujahideen.
-Everyone has been trained in Pashto.
-Pashto?
What if they're trained in Pashto?
What if they get caught?
They'll only get caught
when the Indians reach that height.
Just as we couldn't reach them in Siachen,
this time they won't--
Enough!
Enough of this briefing!
You'll stop this reckless operation that
was undertaken without my knowledge.
Wait for my further orders.
Let's go.
Mian sahib…
Gandhi, Patel,
Nehru,
Mountbatten,
none of them
wanted Pakistan to be created.
But the Great Leader remained adamant.
There are only a few leaders in the world
who have changed the world map.
And even fewer who have given birth
to a new nation.
If Pakistan exists today,
it is because of Muhammad Ali Jinnah.
We have snatched
a big chunk of Kashmir from India.
And if we remain adamant this time,
then like the Great Leader,
you will change
the map of this world, sir.
General sahib, I came here
for a military briefing.
Not for advice on political matters.
I told you, Pervez sahib,
no more surprises.
But you seem to have forgotten that
you're the Army Chief of this country,
not the Prime Minister.
Remember that going forward.
Let's go.
Such a huge operation
and none of us got a whiff of it?
So… what's the plan going forward?
What's the plan?
Now we have to find
a new army chief, Abba ji.
Have you seen his audacity?
Without asking me,
without the Prime Minister's permission,
he has pulled this stunt.
Is this the right time
to remove General Musharraf?
What…
What are you saying, Abba ji?
Are you even listening?
I told you,
running a country
is like running a business.
And to remain in the business of politics,
you have to be on the winning side.
A victory you couldn't achieve
during the peace talks…
if Musharraf manages to achieve it
without you,
where will you be left standing?
Which is why, if he's winning the war,
this operation should be the PM's.
Yours.
If you prove worthy of this moment,
history will truly place you
alongside Jinnah sahib.
Reconvene the Cabinet this evening.
Call General Musharraf too.
Boys,
we are the eyes of the nation now.
-And that's a huge responsibility.
-And a very difficult one too.
One thousand to two thousand feet.
As a low-altitude photo-recce squadron,
we're trained to take photos
from these heights.
Now, the enemy is sitting here…
at 18,000 feet.
Temperature, minus 25 degrees,
wind speed, 100 kilometers per hour.
So we have to get here to take the photo.
Twenty thousand feet.
We know very well that
our MiGs aren't designed
for these heights or conditions.
Unfortunately, they know this
well enough too.
To conceal our approach,
we will fly through the valley
and approach the target sector,
then climb without warning
and fly over the enemy sector.
There are mountains on both sides.
A minor slip,
and you will crash.
Ahuja and I will fly the first sortie.
Will one sortie be enough?
Will we be able to capture
their exact locations?
Even I don't know this.
All we know is that in the history
of the Indian Air Force,
no photo-recce squadron
has ever played such a critical role.
We're the select chosen few
who've been given the opportunity
to protect our borders.
Golden Arrows, are we ready?
Yes, sir.
-Are we ready?
-Yes, sir.
-Yes, sir!
Plans for tomorrow?
Depends, sir.
Let's see how today's recce goes.
Ideally, we should do
multiple sorties with the boys.
I'm talking about your birthday.
Birthday plans at a time like this, sir?
In any case, one ends up
with over 100 birthdays in a year.
Celebrating just one day
would be undervaluing oneself, right?
Isn't every successful landing
a birthday, sir?
Your twisted logic on this too.
The whole world runs
on twisted logic, sir.
Otherwise, who'd fight
for these barren mountains?
See you on the other side.
Will do, sir.
Setting course for IP.
Roger, sir.
Arrow 2, careful.
We're in the valley now.
Roger, on your tail.
Arrow 1, strong cross winds
are pushing you to the right.
Abort valley approach, Arrow 1.
Arrow 2, we'll have to fight it.
Arrow 1, we might crash into the mountain.
It's too late, Arrow 2.
Start crabbing now!
Maintaining RPM and altitude,
keep nosing up.
Maintaining, Arrow 1.
Arrow 2, stand by for left exit.
Roger.
Be ready to exit the valley.
Mindful on your left!
Exit valley now!
That was close, Arrow 2.
This will be tough for the boys.
We need a plan B for the valley approach.
Strongly agree, Arrow 1.
Arrow 2, banking left 45 degrees
for better visual.
Roger.
I'll bank 45 degrees and see, sir.
Come on, everyone, in the sangar. Quick!
Cover it. Everybody, hide. Move it!
All I can see is snow everywhere.
Arrow 1, I think I've spotted something.
Marking coordinates for you.
What are you suggesting, Arrow 2?
I feel, we should take another pass.
A little lower.
All right. Fuel check?
Joker plus hundred. Plenty of fuel.
Exercise caution, Arrow 2.
Hostile fire possible.
The jets are coming back.
Approaching target. Turn on cameras.
Cameras on standby.
Target in five, four, three, two, one.
-Cameras on.
Arrow 2, did you spot anything
during the second pass?
-I did see something.
-What?
Not sure, sir.
But there's something.
Let's see.
I'll take it.
You guys get Tony's reel.
-Sir, I can do that--
-Didn't I tell you?
Take the reel
from Tony sir's jet and go to PIC.
I need these reels developed by evening.
Good evening, Mian sahib.
I conducted myself wrongly with you.
I'm sorry.
Don't say that, Mian sahib.
Your anger is justified.
But our goal was to keep you
all insulated till the right time came.
General,
the way you kept the operation secret
is highly commendable.
Operation Mountaineering.
That's the name of the operation.
And now Mountaineering
is our responsibility too.
-You just said it.
-Absolutely, Mian sahib.
Our men have done their job.
Now all of you have to leverage
this situation diplomatically.
Sartaj sahib.
Sir?
What's the international reaction
to this issue?
Sir, Indians are leaning towards
Russian support.
And the US?
America, as expected, is neutral for now.
I think, we should talk to China.
If we get China's support,
India will be cornered
not just militarily,
but on the diplomatic front too.
That works too.
Then the ISI chief
and I will talk to Beijing.
Nawaz,
I think
General Musharraf should go to China.
To open a channel with a military state,
who better than the Army Chief?
Jai Hind, sir.
Jai Hind. Yes, Patil?
-It's an emergency.
-What kind of emergency?
I don't know, sir.
Tony sir is calling you.
He is a jolly good fellow
And so say all of us
-Ahuja, happy birthday.
-Sir!
-Happy birthday.
-Thank you, sir.
Happy birthday, dear Ahuja sir
Happy birthday to you
Alka ma'am loves you
Good one.
We all love you…
Flying officer Dhaliwal.
Happy birthday to you
Okay, I will. Hold on.
Sir, the pictures are ready.
Here…
Project this negative.
This.
Just this area.
Get me a printout of this.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir, these are enlargements
of our recce photos.
If you look at these magnified images,
footsteps are clearly visible on the snow.
But these footprints aren't random.
They're a single coordinated trail.
Mujahideen don't move in single file.
It's the army that moves in single file.
Sir, why would Mujahideen move
in such a regimental manner,
that too in such harsh snowy conditions?
They can walk across
any unguarded place as they like.
I agree with the Air Chief.
This looks to be
the Pakistan Army's doing.
R&AW has intercepted radio calls.
They are speaking in Pashto,
but discussing army protocols.
If we analyze the depth of this trail,
it's clear that this trail
was not used just once.
It's been used repeatedly.
This means they've been sitting
on our peaks for quite some time,
building bases.
Historically, sir,
Mujahideen cross the LoC
and carry out small attacks.
Why would they build bases on peaks?
Gentlemen,
I believe
we are faced with a limited invasion
by the Pakistani Army.
This is not just deceit,
but a betrayal of our trust by Pakistan.
And we
will respond to this betrayal.
I…
give permission to the Indian Air Force
to commence bombing.
Sir.
But
on one condition.
We have to respect the Line of Control.
Because they want us
to cross the border,
so that they can tell the world…
"We didn't do anything in Kargil,
but India is crossing the border."
Then due to the fear
of nuclear escalation,
UK, France,
US, Russia,
the entire international community
will pressure us into a ceasefire.
And where everyone is positioned right now
will become the new de-facto LoC.
This ploy of theirs
is the biggest challenge of this war.
We cannot cross the LoC and strike,
or we cannot cross the LoC at all?
Both.
We can only attack from our side,
on the captured peaks.
But, Chief,
the basic principle
for any air force in the world
is to go across the line
and neutralize enemy infrastructure.
How will our fighters find targets
in this white ocean, sir?
I don't know.
I just know
that if we don't do anything now,
all that'll be left of our ground forces
out there in the snow
will be corpses. Corpses.
Operation Safed Sagar.
The prime minister
has authorized air strikes in this war.
We're ready, sir.
We've marked their supply routes.
Marked their forward bases too.
We'll cross the LoC tomorrow morning
and start bombing.
But we know that
as soon as we cross the LoC,
their F-16s may get airborne.
So our MiG-29s--
Their F-16s will not get airborne.
Because we…
will not cross the LoC.
Sir, it's almost impossible
to hit such small camouflaged targets
at these heights.
No air force in the world
has ever done this.
So? The Indian Air Force
will be the first.
Because if we cross the LoC,
the conflict will escalate.
Pakistan will demand a ceasefire
at international forums.
And where the intruders
are currently positioned,
that will de-facto become the new LoC.
And we'll lose our land.
We must understand
that this is also a diplomatic war now.
I know. I'm asking you
to strike with your hands tied.
The Army has started Operation Vijay.
Now, either we support them
or sit at home
and watch their losses telecast live.
So, gentlemen,
is the Indian Air Force
ready for this war?
Yes, sir!
Operation Safed Sagar
starts tomorrow at 0700 hours.
The ongoing Kargil conflict between India
and Pakistan has taken a new turn.
Home Minister Lal Krishna Advani,
speaking to reporters, said…
They have violated the Simla Agreement,
violated the Lahore Declaration.
Mercenaries who have been
sent across the border,
but it is Pakistani regulars.
Pakistan Army Regulars.
Soon after, a massive deployment
of the Indian Army was seen
in the Drass and Kargil sectors.
And for the first time in history,
two nuclear armed nations
appear to be heading towards
a direct confrontation.
Addressing the nation today,
Indian Prime Minister Vajpayee
had this to say…
The world has seen that we want peace.
And now the world will see
that to protect this peace,
we can also demonstrate our strength.
Vajpayee sahib,
this is not the Pakistan Army,
these are Mujahideen.
Before making an announcement
to the international media,
you could have at least spoken to me once?
Sir, our government has no power
over these Mujahideen.
Mian sahib,
power is the very definition
of government.
A government that has no power
is not a government at all.
Mian sahib, with our joint efforts,
a new hope had arisen
among people of both countries.
Remember, Mian sahib, both countries
will never
be able to recover from this treachery.
-Arrows?
-Arrows.
-Sir.
You couldn't sleep either, sir?
This is my first war too.
But nothing comes of studying
the night before an exam.
Shall we do something else?
At ease, boys.
Two Truths and a Lie.
-Ever played it?
-No, sir.
Everyone gets to tell two truths
and one lie about themselves.
And everyone else has to deduce
which one is the lie.
-Sounds like your game, sir.
-Correct.
So I'll go first?
I always wanted to join the Air Force.
I said yes to marrying Alka
when she made me
a great cup of coffee in under a minute.
Tony. Tony hated me
the first time he met me.
-Easy.
-This is easy, sir.
Start guessing.
The Tony sir thing is a lie. I'm sure.
What Tony sir?
The Alka ma'am thing is a lie.
No, he can't hate him.
-Who can make coffee in a minute?
-Last option.
One can't agree to marriage on a cup
of coffee. Obviously, it's Alka ma'am.
It looks like Tony sir to me.
-Yes, Tony sir.
-Tony sir.
-Baldy said it.
-Time's up.
Tony sir for me and Goofy.
The last option.
-Alka ma'am. Yeah.
-Alka ma'am, sir.
Damn.
All wrong.
Why?
I did not always want
to join the Air Force.
Just… Sir, just a sec.
Did you say yes over good coffee?
Yes, buddy.
I thought if someone can make
such good coffee in just a minute,
how much time will she save daily?
How much extra time
we both would have
to live our lives.
I said yes.
Sir, if I may ask, don't take me wrong.
Why did Alka ma'am say yes?
She must've had a reason too.
Just asking.
This you will have to ask
your Alka madam only.
She hasn't told me till date.
-But still, sir, who says yes over coffee?
-Yes, sir, coffee?
Hercules tower, line up runway one-three,
and report ready for departure.
Hercules formation. Cleared to take off.
Winds three o'clock. 10 kilometers.
Stop time 1.2 kilometers.
Traffic ahead of you. Hyena formation.
Climbing, passing 1.5 kilometers.
0800 IST.
9 Squadron.
-Dash, Nishi.
-Sir!
Hyena 1 and Hyena 2
will drop bombs on Point 4065.
Entering from the eastern heading,
they will exit on the southeast side.
Hyena formation over IP.
We're heading towards the target.
Hyena formation, breaking off.
Ahuja, Dhali.
-Sir!
Hercules 1 and Hercules 2.
You will hold at 55 kilometers southeast.
Upon receiving RT confirmation,
you will cross the target area.
In two minutes, you will cross the target
area and assess bomb damage.
Hercules, standby
for bombing confirmation.
Hercules standing by. Hit them hard, boys.
Captain Waheed.
-Sir.
-Take out the Stinger.
And, everyone else, hide in the sangars!
Yes, sir.
Put it down.
Captain Waheed, hurry up.
I am on it, sir.
What are you doing? Hurry up.
Yes, sir. I'm trying to get a lock.
Hurry up, you will miss them.
Fire!
Oh, shit!
Stinger fire suspected.
Climbing to get out of missile range.
Hyena 1, climb!
How did it miss?
Sir, I fired without getting a lock.
Mayday, mayday, mayday!
Hyena 2, engine flameout. Ejecting!
Rasool, connect to Skardu.
What happened?
Sir, Nishi's jet flamed out.
He was climbing 25,000 feet, sir.
To avoid SAMs.
Sir, an Indian jet has crashed!
On its own, sir.
Ground all jets immediately.
Hercules formation, abort mission.
Abort mission.
Hercules, if you read me,
return to base immediately.
Hostile fire reported in the area.
Hyena 2 has ejected.
Copy that.
Khan, did he eject safely?
Negative, we do not have his coordinates.
We're in the same sector.
We'll try to find him.
There are Stingers out there, Hercules.
You have only cameras.
Along with our cameras,
we also have GPS, sir.
We can tell you his exact coordinates.
You do not have any protection.
Return to base immediately.
It is too risky.
-Hyena 1 is returning to base.
-Negative.
We can't return without Hyena 2.
You're deviating
from your planned mission.
Will you please stop
arguing with me, Khan?
I need five minutes. I will find Nishi.
Hercules. Let's do this.
-Fuel check.
-Roger.
Hercules 1. Joker.
I have fuel.
Hercules 2, fuel check.
Hercules 2.
Joker.
Sir, correction, sir.
My needle just jumped.
Be clear, Hercules 2.
Joker or thirsty?
It's thirsty, sir.
Sorry, but my fuel suddenly dipped.
-We have to go back.
-You have to go back.
-Hercules 1, you need to abort as well.
-Negative.
Nishi is alone.
I won't come back until I find him.
Sir, but it's too risky.
You're low on fuel, Hercules 2.
You can be a liability.
But there has to be someone to cover
your tail. It's too risky out there--
That's an order, Hercules 2.
Return to base.
Chin up, soldier.
I'll see you in 20 minutes.
We'll have coffee.
Take care, sir.
Hercules 2, breaking off.
I don't see anything.
I don't have a clear visual.
Need to fly lower.
No, Hercules 1, you can't.
It's too risky.
And you don't have much fuel left.
Enough fuel for one more pass, sir.
I've got this.
Another jet is here!
Reload the SAM again. Hurry!
This time, get a lock and then fire.
It's here.
I have visual. Wreckage spotted.
Khan, stand by for coordinates.
Copy coordinates.
"343833 North,
763524 East."
Roger that, Hercules 1.
Now get the hell out of there.
Roger. Will do that.
-Ready, Captain?
-Yes, sir.
We shouldn't miss this time.
Stinger spotted!
Mayday, mayday, mayday!
Stinger hit!
Roger that, Hercules 1.
We've got you on radar. Call ejecting.
Sir, another Indian jet has crashed!
This time, we shot it down!
Ahuja, can you hear me?
Losing control.
Looking for valley to eject.
Copy coordinates. "344108 North,
762226 East."
Roger that, Hercules 1.
-Call ejecting.
-Ejecting now!
Subtitle translation by Monika Saraf